# **Ben Deavin**

Senior Engineering Manager

♥ Woking, UK♦ bendeavin.co.ukIinkedin.com/in/bendeavin∮ github.com/bendeavin

## **Professional Summary**

Experienced leader and manager with a deep technical background spanning multiple tech stacks, architectural patterns, industries and organisation set ups. Focused on developing a great working culture through outstanding communication and building genuine relationships where everyone feels heard and valued. Able to quickly understand complex systems and problem spaces and effectively plan and deliver the right solutions given the wider context.

#### **Professional Skills**

- People & Team Management
   Hiring, development, career progression, coaching leaders, organizational design
- Project & Delivery
   Planning, management, agile methodologies
- Community & Communication
   Leading communities, senior stakeholder engagement
- Product Strategy
   AB testing, prototyping, feature scoping

#### **Technical Skills**

- Distributed systems & microservices Event-driven architecture, micro frontends
- Full stack development
   TypeScript, React, Java, Groovy, C#
- Testing & QA
   TDD, integration, E2E, contract, visual regression
- Cloud & Performance
   AWS, GCP, serverless, Core Web Vitals
- Developer Experience CI/CD, environment optimization, workflow improvement

### **Work Experience**

#### Secret Escapes

Senior Engineering Manager (2023 - Present) Engineering Manager (2019 - 2023) Tech Lead (2017 - 2019) September 2017 - Present (7y 9m)

- Team Leadership: Overseeing three product development squads in the 'member experience' space, accountable for core delivery metrics and cross-squad communication
- People Management: Managing a mix of managers, leads and individual contributors, mentoring, coaching and guiding their career development
- **Team Building:** Responsible for hiring and building new squads, establishing ways of working and quickly getting to a place of high performance
- **Technical Leadership:** Frontend community lead, bringing specialists from multiple squads together to share experience and shape our technical direction in the frontend space
- Performance Optimization: Responsible for frontend performance, establishing tooling and budgets for monitoring Core Web Vitals across multiple platforms and prioritising improvements
- Strategic Planning: Key contributor to strategy, at multiple levels including group architecture and both tech and product strategy and project planning
- **Technical Delivery:** Lead the delivery of several new microservices including rebuilding search capability from the ground up with OpenSearch (formally ElasticSearch)

#### **PA Consulting Group**

January 2013 - September 2017 (4y 9m)

**Consultant** (2015 - 2017) **Consultant Analyst** (2013 - 2015)

- Tech Lead: Technical lead on a team for a large public sector project, working with a mixture of contractors, civil servants and consultants. Building a microservices platform and case working system
- Cloud Architect: Designing and implementing a scalable architecture for a large IoT project with up to 200,000 connected devices running on Google Cloud Platform
- Lead Android Developer: Team lead for a fast moving technology start up, taking a complex app from concept to production in four months, managing a scrum team of five developers
- Software Engineer: Various projects working as a full stack developer, working with clients to gather and manage requirements, and working with skilled teams (both on and offshore) delivering excellent quality and timely releases
- Wearable Technology Expert: Working with numerous clients helping them see the potential
  of wearable technology and developing numerous prototypes with Google Glass, Android
  Wear and more

# Smarta Enterprise Ltd Web Developer

August 2010 - January 2013 (2y 5m)

- **Web Developer:** .NET web developer, working on the Smarta Business Builder, a SaaS portal integrating a number of third party products into one service
- Full Stack Development: Working on all aspects of the project, including database, serverside code, partner APIs, security, and front end HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- System Design: Designed various parts of the system, including leading a ground-up construction of an email messaging centre that gave all products a unified platform to reliably send and track emails
- **Product Improvement:** Identified ways to improve the product from design and user experience changes to adding new features and functionality and improving performance

#### **Goldman Sachs**

June 2008 – June 2009 (1y placement)

**Industrial Work Placement** 

- Software Developer: Infrastructure and middleware as part of the work placement scheme
- Development: Designing, developing, testing and deploying tools to help with messaging
- System Deployment: Deployed application on distributed UNIX based systems
- Project Ownership: Took ownership of a major project from start through to support

#### Education

# **BSc Computer Science (with industrial placement)**

First Class Honours

University of Bath | 2006 - 2010

#### Interests & Hobbies

Time with family • Travel • Photography • Drumming and music •

Technical side projects • Emerging technologies & gadgets